James Maciukenas, Ph.D.

blueform@gmail.com theresomewhere.github.io

Profile

Designer, Developer, and Researcher with experience as strategic member of academic leadership teams. Earned a Ph.D. in Technical Communication exploring user experience through qualitative and quantitative research. Establishes rapport and credibility with diverse groups. Recognized for being a team player with strengths in analysis and implementing constraint-based solutions that work.

Experience

Web Developer, Indiana University-Bloomington, IN – 2019-Present

Server migrations, CMS, faculty research website builds, data collection/processing.

Web Developer and Adjunct Instructor, DePaul University, Chicago, IL - 2019

Web design and development for Advancement Office

Developed curricula and taught graduate and undergraduate online and in-classroom courses in: Web Design Tools Workshop; Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction.

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL - 2005-Present

Senior Web Development & Graphic Design Coordinator - 2011-2019

Integrated design thinking and UX research methods to deliver innovative and useful communication solutions for online and print audiences of IIT College of Science.

Adjunct Instructor – 2006-Present

Developed curricula and taught graduate and undergraduate online and in-classroom courses in: Usability; Web Design and Development; Document Design; Technical Communication; Publication Management; and Public Engagement for Scientists.

Department Coordinator; Project and Communications Associate - 2005-2011

Completed web, print, and branding projects to raise awareness with prospective student, peer, alumni, and industry audiences.

Consulting

Newcity Communications, Inc., Chicago, IL - 2015-2019

Supported Wordpress websites, designed and prepared Newcity Magazine for production.

Volunteering

Web Developer and Assistant Coach, AYSO Youth Soccer, Evanston, IL – 2016-2019 Creative Director/Web Developer and Assistant Coach, Chicago, IL – 2014-2019

Creative Director/Web Developer, Ordinary People International, Chicago, IL - 2011-Present

Education

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL – Ph.D. in Technical Communication, 2013 Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL – M.S. in Technical Communication and

Information Design, 2007

Concordia University, Montreal, QC – Graduate Certificate in Digital Technologies in Design

Art Practice

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL – B.F.A. in Industrial Design

References

Available upon request.